man I love me some dumbbells the
versatility is hard to beat but my
goodness it can be tough to find the
right amount of space for a full set so
thankfully we do have adjustable
dumbbells nowadays that can take the
place of a full set now I think we all
know how traditional adjustable
dumbbells work you know sliding plates
on and off and securing them down with a
weight collar now some companies
definitely still make adjustable
dumbbells like that but the Bowflex
selectec 552s and the nuo bills both
feature an Innovative design that makes
adjusting the weight as easy as one two
three that way you can just grab your
weight and get right to your workout
foreign
yo what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym with another
comparison review for you all today this
time I'm going to be comparing the
Bowflex select Tech 552s and the nuo
bells and I'm going to help you decide
which ones that need to be in your home
gym but before I get going with all of
that I gotta let you know we've reviewed
a lot of adjustable dumbbells on
barbin.com so if you want to browse our
best list just go ahead and search
barbend best adjustable dumbbells and
you can find out for yourself which ones
that we like the best
[Music]
foreign
so let's talk about the similarities
with these two adjustable dumbbells
first and foremost they replace at least
15 individual pairs of dumbbells at a
much cheaper price tag and they only
require a fraction of the footprints
anybody living in an apartment or you're
just tied on space in general you can't
go wrong with either one of these
options they both feature a cradle it
comes with your purchase that way you
can store your dumbbells and the plates
that you aren't using for your workout
and adjusting the weight is a super
simple process with both of these
adjustable dumbbells so no more having
to slide plates on and off and securing
them down with a weight collar just
simply give a Twist get straight to your
workout
foreign
[Music]
between these two adjustable dumbbells
then there are similarities let's kick
this off with the build of each so
Bowflex is using a lot of plastic here
with the 552s minus a couple of features
such as the handle all the newer bells
are mostly made of steel except for you
do have a little bit of plastic here
just to hold the heads of the dumbbell
to the handle speaking of handles the
new availables have a fully knurled
handle that does have a uniform design
it's also how you're going to be
adjusting the weight so to do that all
you have to do is Twist the handle while
with the 552s they do in fact have an
ergonomic design with the handle so it's
thicker in the middle than it is on the
ends it does feature a rubber grip in
the middle which might you know might
not be the best grip for everybody it
has it's been totally fine for me it's
obviously a personal preference and to
adjust the weight with the 552s you're
going to twist these knobs on either end
to get the right weight you want when
you go to work out so when it comes to
the max weight with the newer Bells you
actually have two different options you
go from five to fifty pounds or five to
eighty like we have right here and with
the 552s you're maxing out at 52 and a
half pounds now when it comes to the
increments 552s actually has some two
and a half pound increments for you to
work with it's actually pretty cool
actually really helpful when it comes to
working out with dumbbells and with the
Nua Bells you're stuck with five pound
increments all the way throughout and
while it may look like the newer bills
are bigger sitting right here in front
of me when you're working out the size
of the new available is actually going
to change and it kind of feels like a
traditional dumbbell while with the 552s
they definitely feel longer in my
opinion and the size of these is not
going to change whether you're using
five pounds or 52 and a half pounds it's
going to be the same length regardless
and when it comes to price
the 552s are significantly cheaper
all right so let's compare the pricing
now with both of these adjustable
dumbbells the 552s are going to run you
around 470 bucks that's including
shipping and taxes now with the nuo
bills once again you have two different
options so the five to fifty pound bills
are a shade under 600 bucks while the 5
to 80s that I have right here are about
750 dollars now this plastic cradle is
included with your purchase with the nuo
bills but if you want you can opt in for
a beefier steel one if you choose to the
gray one is going to be around 185 bucks
while the black one is going to be about
195 dollars and plus you have to tack on
shipping which is an additional 100 now
it's no secret that the new availables
are gonna cost you a lot more money than
the 552s are especially if you go for
that five to eighty pound set we have
right here so if you're on a pretty
tight budget or you know maybe you just
don't need 80 pounds of weight I think
you're definitely gonna be better off
going with the 552s but because of the
amount of plastic that's mixed in with
these adjustable dumbbells it might be
better to go for the new oil balance for
some people because of the amount of
Steel that's used because they might
last you longer
okay so let's talk about the build and
some of the features you're going to
find with both of these adjustable
dumbbells but I want to start with the
552s once again you do have an
ergonomically shaped handle so it's
thicker in the middle than it is on the
ends closest to the heads of the
dumbbell now I don't know the exact
handle diameter but comparing it to your
average ergonomically shaped handle on
dumbbells it's about 35 millimeters or
so this handle is made from steel it
does feature a rubber grip in the middle
of the handle might not provide
everybody with that sticky tack grip
that they're looking for but you know in
my opinion I've had no problem with it
while I'm working out now once again you
do have a lot of plastic mixed in right
here other than that handle and really
the mechanism located within the
dumbbells are here to adjust the weight
and to do that all you have to do is
simply twist these knobs that are
located on either end and that way
you're going to be able to really select
the exact plates that you want it's
super very easy to do so you can simply
pull right out and you can be able to
grab you know exactly the weight that
you need now
ours have gotten a lot of usage to say
the least out of them so every once in a
while you know they will get stuck
either in the Cradle or just the
adjustment mechanism whenever I'm going
to change the weight so keep that in
mind you know over time the plastic here
might wear down a little bit and you
might experience some sticking during
your workouts all right so let's
transition to the new bills now start
with the handles here it's the fully
knurled handle it's about a medium
knurling it also has a chrome plating on
it to help you fight against some Rust
and corrosion over time I don't know the
exact diameter of the handles but it
seems to be right around 30 millimeters
when you compare it to other dumbbells
out there that do not feature an
ergonomic handle now other than the
plastic used to hold the handle and the
heads together there's really no plastic
used with the actual dumbbells now the
Cradle still has a good amount of
plastic used right here so you
definitely want to be careful when you
go to store your dumbbells but other
than that it seems to be really durable
in my my opinion so to adjust the weight
all you have to do is Twist the handle
you can fly through all the available
options and just so you know you know
which weight you're using there's a
little indicator on either side of the
handle as well as indicators showing you
you know if you twist to the right you
go up and wait twist to the left you're
going to go down and weight so that's
really nice you always know what weight
you're using and to do that here I'll
show you a little example right here
let's put it on 25 pounds and you pull
it up and as you see I mentioned this
earlier you know the size of the actual
dumbbell is going to be impacted on the
weight you're using so if I were to have
this on 80 pounds I mean I would
obviously have all of these plates right
here so it's going to be much bigger
than it would be with it when it was
with 25 pounds like I just had now with
the 552s obviously that doesn't matter
whether you're using five pounds 52 and
a half pounds that's going to be the
same length no matter what
all right guys let's go and do a quick
walk around with both of these
adjustable dumbbells let's start start
with the 552s once again you know you do
have a good amount of plastic used right
here from the plates really to
everything here other than the handle
and the adjustment mechanism that's
inside the actual dumbbell itself so
let's go ahead and show you once again
how to adjust the weight super easy all
you have to do is simply twist right
here you'll be able to see exactly which
weight you're doing you want to do that
on both sides or else you know these are
going to be locked and they're not going
to pull out on you so when you do that
you'll see you know it's not selecting
all the weights obviously but the size
is the exact same no matter what so if I
had this at 52 and a half pounds it
would still be just as long right here
so that could be a little bit of an
issue for some people probably going to
change the motion for some of your
workouts like a bicep curl if I have to
you know adjust accordingly with these
dumbbells you do have a rubber grip
right here in the middle and it might
not be you know the best thing in the
world for every single person out there
but I gotta say you know it's totally
fine for me my hands sweat a little bit
hit when I'm working out and I think
it's totally fine you know but that's
personal preference now if we transition
to the nuo bells you know once again you
do have fully knurled handle right here
and I do get a little bit better of a
grip as I'm working out and might as
well now to adjust the weight with these
you know you just do a little twist and
you're going to see right here which
weight you're using it's going to be
super easy for you either twist to the
right or to the left to get that weight
and when you pull these out
look how much smaller that is I mean
these are both on 10 pounds right now so
I gotta say you know the nuo bells
definitely feel more traditional in a
sense of their size because you know
they're about what a traditional
dumbbell size is and that's obviously
not the case with the Bowflex 552s
foreign
[Music]
so which of these adjustable dumbbells
do you need to buy well I say it a lot
you know this really just boils down to
personal preference and that's no
different here these are essentially
same product but they're not identical
right so I think it's really important
that you weigh the pros and the cons of
each and really focus on the price the
materials used as well as how much
weight you specifically need so you want
to save some money definitely think the
552s are gonna be your best bet but
remember there's a lot of plastic used
here so you do run the risk of them
cracking on you over time and also over
time you know there's a good chance that
the plastic here is going to get worn
down a little bit so it'll probably get
stuck on you like ours tend to do from
time to time something you shouldn't
really have to worry about too much with
the newer Bells because they do in fact
feature pretty much all steel and if you
need more than 50 pounds of weight then
you obviously want to snag the nuo bells
as well but they're obviously a lot more
expensive and lastly you know if you do
in fact want the best grip possible and
I think this fully knurled handle with
the newer Bells is just going to get the
job done better well guys that's all I
have for you today on this comparison
between the Bowflex selectec 552s and
the nuo bells these are both going to be
a great option for anybody who's tight
on space but does in fact want some
dumbbells to work out with you know
they're going to be significantly
cheaper than a full set would be plus
they require a fraction of the footprint
thanks for watching everybody I hope
this video was really helpful and that I
was able to answer any questions you may
have about both of these adjustable
dumbbells as always stay on the lookout
for my next video but for now head over
to barbin.com and you can read more
about this comparison just search
barbend Bowflex adjustable dumbbells
versus new Avail adjustable dumbbells
you can find everything that I talked
about here today I'll catch y'all later
[Music]
thank you
foreign